<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Objektiv Digital</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 18:05:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>/app/uploads/2020/08/cropped-objektiv-favicon-100x100.png</url>
	<title>Objektiv Digital</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>An Open Letter to Solicitors and Salespeople</title>
		<link>/2020/11/12/an-open-letter-to-solicitors-and-salespeople/</link>
					<comments>/2020/11/12/an-open-letter-to-solicitors-and-salespeople/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian McKenzie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 18:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1807</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Dear salesperson, Thank you for contacting us regarding the services you’re offering. Here are the reasons we will not be using your services: You clicked our ad, thereby making your prospecting efforts cost us money that is supposed to be spent on prospective clients You filled out a contact form that was obviously designed, written, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/11/12/an-open-letter-to-solicitors-and-salespeople/">An Open Letter to Solicitors and Salespeople</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Dear salesperson,</p>



<p>Thank you for contacting us regarding the services you’re offering. Here are the reasons we will not be using your services:</p>



<ol><li>You clicked our ad, thereby making your prospecting efforts cost us money that is supposed to be spent on prospective clients</li><li>You filled out a contact form that was obviously designed, written, and formatted for prospective clients, not solicitors</li><li>You filled out that form instead of scrolling to the footer of our website and using the&nbsp;<a class="" href="mailto:contact@objektiv.digital">contact@objektiv.digital</a>&nbsp;email address that is displayed for salespeople like you</li><li>Because you clicked our ad and submitted our form made for prospective clients, you made yourself get tracked as a conversion on our ad which then shut off any further impressions for that day because your conversion made our ad meet its conversion threshold for the day</li><li>Because you made us reach our conversion threshold, we are now no longer getting a legitimate lead, thereby throttling our ability to make sales</li><li>Additionally, because Google’s algorithms now have you tracked as a conversion, it is going to try delivering our ad to more salespeople like you, rather than to prospective paying customers — also something that throttles our sales</li><li>Because you have throttled our ability to make sales, we are now not able to make the money necessary to grow our business — growth that could have led to us hiring someone like you</li></ol>



<p>We are trying really hard to keep in mind that you are a fellow human being that deserves the same compassion and respect that we do – we&#8217;re trying not to use expletives at you right now. We truly hope that you can identify the frustration that your actions have caused our marketing and sales team. We hope this email helps to educate you on becoming a more effective and ethical salesperson. We hope you are able to see how your actions hurt our sales and yours. We hope that when you decide to do better, it will result in people like us, and like you, becoming more prosperous businesspeople.</p>



<p>Thank you for your consideration,</p>



<p>Objektiv Digital</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/11/12/an-open-letter-to-solicitors-and-salespeople/">An Open Letter to Solicitors and Salespeople</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/11/12/an-open-letter-to-solicitors-and-salespeople/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Emotional Design</title>
		<link>/2020/06/25/emotional-design/</link>
					<comments>/2020/06/25/emotional-design/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Fox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 09:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.objektiv.digital/?p=51</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Emotional Design is a concept where the design of the website is meant to evoke an emotional connection with the website&#8217;s viewer. In 2020, and especially now during the COVID-19 pandemic, if you’re not making an emotional connection with your website viewers, you’ve lost them. So what does emotional design look like? I found what [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/06/25/emotional-design/">Emotional Design</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Emotional Design is a concept where the design of the website is meant to evoke an emotional connection with the website&#8217;s viewer. In 2020, and especially now during the COVID-19 pandemic, if you’re not making an emotional connection with your website viewers, you’ve lost them. So what does emotional design look like? I found what I think is the best example on the Internet.</p>



<p><em>Let the roads sleep. Because when they wake, we’ll have a lot of catching up to do.</em></p>



<p>Mazda has responded to the pandemic crisis by telling its customers that it’s okay if they sleep (meaning don’t buy new Mazda cars right now), because when things get back to normal the connection they have with Mazda will still be there. They’ve placed this message front and centre on their website to reassure their viewers that Mazda will be here for them. They have connected with their viewers and have built trust by reassuring them that things will get back to normal. The picture they chose to use as a background shows an empty road but there are still signs of life &#8211; the city lights. This is also meant to provide a sense of hope to their users.</p>



<p><strong>This is emotional design</strong> and it works. It is the most reliable way to gain business because it is human. If you take home anything from this blog post, I want it to be a desire to make your websites appeal to your users in an emotional way.</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re worried that emotional design is too soft an approach to selling your products or services, don&#8217;t be. Emotional design is what gets your clients and customers connected to you and your business so that they will naturally want to take action. That&#8217;s why it is important that you place a Call To Action button (Call Now, Book Now, Learn More) right where your website viewer is likely to become emotionally invested &#8211; usually near the top of your landing page (home page). </p>



<p>Mazda placed a Call To Action right in the centre of their emotional design element &#8211; Learn More. They connected with their viewers and then offered them a way that they could purchase from Mazda when the pandemic crisis was under control. That&#8217;s not soft, it&#8217;s smart.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/06/25/emotional-design/">Emotional Design</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/06/25/emotional-design/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who is the best digital marketing agency for your small business?</title>
		<link>/2020/04/14/who-is-the-best-digital-marketing-agency-for-your-small-business/</link>
					<comments>/2020/04/14/who-is-the-best-digital-marketing-agency-for-your-small-business/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian McKenzie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 03:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.objektiv.digital/?p=49</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Long ago when I was developing Stridr, a social media aggregator that helped people discover new people/things to follow on social media, I got one of the best pieces of advice from a friend and mentor I had at the time. At the time, I was feeling pretty frazzled being a one-man tech startup. I [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/04/14/who-is-the-best-digital-marketing-agency-for-your-small-business/">Who is the best digital marketing agency for your small business?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Long ago when I was developing Stridr, a social media aggregator that helped people discover new people/things to follow on social media, I got one of the best pieces of advice from a friend and mentor I had at the time. At the time, I was feeling pretty frazzled being a one-man tech startup. I was getting frustrated at how much there was to do, yet so little time. I was thrown in the deep end on how to manage my time. Here&#8217;s an incomplete list of what I was doing:</p>



<ul><li>Front-end development</li><li>Back-end development</li><li>Dev ops</li><li>Graphic design</li><li>Security updates</li><li>Server optimization</li><li>Art direction</li><li>UX Design</li><li>Bookkeeping</li><li>Facebook ad management</li><li>Twitter ad management</li><li>Pinterest ad management</li></ul>



<p>Compared to what I&#8217;m doing now, that list is tiny. But, the amount of time each position needed added up insanely quick! Even so, I&#8217;d wager it&#8217;s a tiny list compared to most small business owners, including you. But, compared to someone who worked in retail for 10 years, it&#8217;s monumental. I couldn&#8217;t stop whining to my mentor about how much there was to do.</p>



<p>And, while it was not the answer I wanted to hear, he told me something that really stuck with me. He told me that all the time I am putting into those roles is going to position me at a distinct advantage when it comes time to hire someone to replace myself in those roles. He was right. Knowing all of the ways that I worked in those roles, I knew all the good and bad answers to daily challenges. Now, when my employees or contractors tell me something is not possible, I refer back to my expertise and can push back.</p>



<p>This same experience is critical for your marketing. The cold reality of your digital marketing is that if you&#8217;re bootstrapping as much as possible (i.e. hardly any of your revenue is going toward your savings or other long-term financial goals), you need to take the time to learn this stuff yourself. To learn, make mistakes, and find a formula that works. To develop a repeatable process that generates a return on investment. In this sense, the best digital marketing agency for your business is you!</p>



<p>I know, it&#8217;s a terrible answer. It&#8217;s also the most honest answer you&#8217;re going to hear from a digital marketer. The next best thing I can recommend is to hire a digital marketing consultant. They will spend 1 to 2 hours a month with you providing invaluable advice to point you in the right direction, avoid pitfalls, and stop you from making costly mistakes.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/04/14/who-is-the-best-digital-marketing-agency-for-your-small-business/">Who is the best digital marketing agency for your small business?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/04/14/who-is-the-best-digital-marketing-agency-for-your-small-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buyer Beware During Pandemic Altruism from Web Developers</title>
		<link>/2020/03/28/buyer-beware-during-pandemic-altruism-from-web-developers/</link>
					<comments>/2020/03/28/buyer-beware-during-pandemic-altruism-from-web-developers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian McKenzie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 13:19:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.objektiv.digital/?p=47</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is probably going to be a controversial post from within the web developer community, but this is something that needs to be communicated to storefronts weighing their online options to keep their business afloat. This post was somewhat inspired by a great conversation I had with Kris Trudeau at HPX Media about the business [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/03/28/buyer-beware-during-pandemic-altruism-from-web-developers/">Buyer Beware During Pandemic Altruism from Web Developers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This is probably going to be a controversial post from within the web developer community, but this is something that needs to be communicated to storefronts weighing their online options to keep their business afloat. This post was somewhat inspired by a great conversation I had with Kris Trudeau at HPX Media about the business strategy implications of the technology we build for our clients. Across the Comox Valley and Vancouver Island design, tech, and marketing communities that I&#8217;m a part of, I&#8217;m seeing people come together to find ways to solve problems for the local businesses in their community. While this well-natured act is exactly the kind of thing we need during this pandemic, it is ultimately going to cause frustration for the store owners who take advantage of these free services. Why? I will explain by speaking directly to the design, tech, and marketing professionals in our industry.</p>



<p>Offering to help for free is going to hurt the businesses you seek to help. When you build a website, especially an eCommerce website, you are also building a commitment to the business and customers that this website serves. Yes, you are excited and full of energy and want to use your powers for good. But, what happens when you start getting busy? What happens when Betty at Mom &amp; Pop Co. needs to call you 4 times a week to figure out her new eCommerce shop? What happens when you&#8217;ve helped 5 Bettys? How about 10? What happens when Betty has a problem that needs to be solved right now but you didn&#8217;t get around to helping her until 6 o&#8217;clock at night because you&#8217;re still working your day job? What happens 6 months from now when your altruistic vigour has faded but Betty still needs help?</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s be honest with ourselves. We get excited about building something. Creating a fresh design, and building an amazing thing that&#8217;s going to solve so many problems. But eventually, we lose interest. It&#8217;s inevitable. I&#8217;ve seen it over and over with myself and my competition. This is why a financial commitment from clients is absolutely necessary. And it&#8217;s not to serve your personal gain. It&#8217;s not to profit from a tragedy. It&#8217;s to serve your client&#8217;s long term interests. Without financial compensation, you do not have an obligation to serve your clients needs. And your client will be stuck with you and will have to go through the pain of finding another developer to pick up the pieces. And they will feel awkward going to someone else because you were so kind to give them a free website in the first place. It won&#8217;t be fun for them at all, and by the time they find someone else, you&#8217;ll be saying thank god that they&#8217;re not siphoning all that free labor from you.</p>



<p>This scenario happens all the time, and worse yet, it happens even when there is a financial obligation. I have seen so many scenarios play out all the time with even lucrative contracts where the web developer neglects their client to the point of their client starting over in a stressful, costly, and unnecessary way. That risk, in my opinion, is at least ten times more likely to occur when the service provided is free.</p>



<p>If you must use your skills in an altruistic way, do what we&#8217;re doing at Objektiv Digital. We are offering 80% off the design, development, and launching of eCommerce websites for storefront businesses. Creating a tool isn&#8217;t just about creating a tool. It&#8217;s also about considering the long-term business implications that tool has on both your clients and your business needs.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/03/28/buyer-beware-during-pandemic-altruism-from-web-developers/">Buyer Beware During Pandemic Altruism from Web Developers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/03/28/buyer-beware-during-pandemic-altruism-from-web-developers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Ways to Bring Traffic to Your Website</title>
		<link>/2020/03/05/5-ways-to-bring-traffic-to-your-website/</link>
					<comments>/2020/03/05/5-ways-to-bring-traffic-to-your-website/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian McKenzie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 13:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.objektiv.digital/?p=45</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When many people launch their website, they seem to think to themselves, &#8220;Now that I&#8217;m online, all I have to do is sit back and let the numbers roll in.&#8221; Sure, being online helps, but people aren&#8217;t going to come out of nowhere. As a small business, getting people visiting your website generally follows more [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/03/05/5-ways-to-bring-traffic-to-your-website/">5 Ways to Bring Traffic to Your Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When many people launch their website, they seem to think to themselves, &#8220;Now that I&#8217;m online, all I have to do is sit back and let the numbers roll in.&#8221; Sure, being online helps, but people aren&#8217;t going to come out of nowhere. As a small business, getting people visiting your website generally follows more conventional means:</p>



<ul><li>Put your website address everywhere! On your business card and other printed materials, you and your employees&#8217; email signatures, and ensure your website address is appropriately placed on your social media profiles</li><li>Encourage your prospects, customers, friends, family, and everyone else in your network to check out your website</li><li>Make your website a resource for your customers and refer them to those resources</li><li>Hire a search engine optimization (SEO) specialist</li><li>(Advanced) Run ads on social media and search engines</li></ul>



<h2>Put your website address everywhere!</h2>



<p>For some of you, this may seem obvious, but I am always astounded how some businesses seem to make it unnecessarily difficult to find their website. Here are some places you should make sure your website address is on:</p>



<ul><li>Business cards</li><li>Letterheads</li><li>Envelopes</li><li>Brochures and other printed materials</li><li>Swag like pens, totes, mugs, etc.</li><li>You and all of your employees&#8217; company email signatures</li><li>Packaging, price tags, and labels</li><li>Social media profiles (including your personal profiles)</li><li>Google My Business</li><li>Local business improvement association (BIA) profiles</li><li>Websites of non-profit organizations that you have supported</li><li>Websites of business partners, vendors, and people/businesses in your network</li></ul>



<h2>Encourage your prospects, customers, friends, family, and everyone else in your network to check out your website</h2>



<p>Presumably, your website is designed and written in such a way that clearly and concisely describes who you are and what you do. When everyone in your network knows who you are and what you do, the networking effect becomes even more powerful. Not only that, but it helps boost your traffic numbers which can, in a small way, increase your search rankings on Google, Bing, etc.</p>



<h2>Make your website a resource for your customers and refer them to those resources</h2>



<p>When your website becomes a reference point for your customers and the customers of your competitors, it positions you as the authority in your space. It becomes the go-to place for people to learn about the products and services you offer and how to interact with them – and you. When people find value in your website as a source of information, search engines will recognize this and show your website to more people looking for the same information. Here are some ways you can be a valuable source of information:</p>



<ul><li>Maintain a blog where you post at least once a month</li><li>Create pages on your website with Questions and Answers (Q&amp;A) that answer commonly asked questions as it relates to your products or services</li><li>Create guides on how to use/interact/troubleshoot with your product or service</li><li>Create pages with detailed specifications of your product</li><li>Create a blog that documents the success stories of customers who use(d) your product or service</li><li>If you run regular events, post these events on your website and make sure your website can integrate to cross-post these events on Facebook</li><li>(Advanced) Start a podcast with your website as the primary host and index for the podcast. The topic of the podcast is up to you, but it should relate to your products, services or customers in some way</li></ul>



<h2>Hire a search engine optimization (SEO) specialist</h2>



<p>Depending on your industry, getting to the top of a Google Search can be a highly competitive endeavour, and sometimes doing it yourself isn&#8217;t enough. A trained SEO professional can make sure every tiny detail of your website is resolved in such a way that maximizes your search ranking. Additionally, they do routine scans to and analyzing to mitigate the damage of negative SEO campaigns against you.</p>



<h2>(Advanced) Run ads on social media and search engines</h2>



<p>If you&#8217;re not careful, running ads online can be much like gambling at the casino. You throw down $100 and can easily see it disappear into thin air. Our recommendation is to run 4 to 8 $2/day ads with multiple variations between device type used, demographics, and other data related to the prospective customer. Run the ads for a few days and shut off the ads that are the least performant. When you feel comfortable that you have found a formula that provides a worthwhile return on investment, you may want to consider increasing the budget.<br>At the end of the day, however, knowing how to run a successful ad can take months or even years of experience. Depending on your product or service, you may want to consider hiring a professional to manage your digital advertising.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/03/05/5-ways-to-bring-traffic-to-your-website/">5 Ways to Bring Traffic to Your Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/03/05/5-ways-to-bring-traffic-to-your-website/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>8 Things Your Web Designer / Developer Should Be Doing for You</title>
		<link>/2020/02/01/8-things-your-web-designer-developer-should-be-doing-for-you/</link>
					<comments>/2020/02/01/8-things-your-web-designer-developer-should-be-doing-for-you/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian McKenzie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 22:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.objektiv.digital/?p=43</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Before entering into a lengthy contract and/or getting your digital assets locked into a website developer/host&#8217;s hands, it&#8217;s important to know what you&#8217;re getting yourself into. All too often, I&#8217;ve talked to business owners that cannot easily update their website (if at all!), their website gets hacked all the time, or their host/developer is seldom [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/02/01/8-things-your-web-designer-developer-should-be-doing-for-you/">8 Things Your Web Designer / Developer Should Be Doing for You</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Before entering into a lengthy contract and/or getting your digital assets locked into a website developer/host&#8217;s hands, it&#8217;s important to know what you&#8217;re getting yourself into. All too often, I&#8217;ve talked to business owners that cannot easily update their website (if at all!), their website gets hacked all the time, or their host/developer is seldom available — and when they are available they are either impatient or do not follow even basic instructions when you ask them to do something. There&#8217;s a myriad of problems that can come up from having a website developer that is not holding up their end of the bargain.</p>



<p>The truth is, many website developers want you locked into their technology and maintenance contract so that they can make a recurring revenue from you, all while making it as hard as possible for you to switch to anyone else. They often have lengthy contracts to further compound the difficulty of switching. Having a contract with a set term isn&#8217;t inherently bad. Nor is charging a monthly fee. But, web developers often do not hold up their end of the bargain when it comes to providing services that align with the amount of money they are charging you each month.</p>



<p>I have come up with a basic set of questions to ask your current or prospective web developer:</p>



<ol><li>Does your host or website developer make regular improvements and bug fixes to your site?</li><li>Does your host or website developer perform automatic, weekly, or monthly security audits and fixes?</li><li>Does your website developer provide phone and email support?</li><li>If yes to #3, are they almost always friendly, patient, helpful, and prompt in resolving your issues?</li><li>Does your web developer provide support with managing your domain?</li><li>Does your web developer have a dedicated server or virtual machine for your website?</li><li>Does your web developer monitor server load and scale your website during instances of rapid growth or going viral?</li><li>Can you make an update to your website&#8217;s content without getting help from your website developer?</li></ol>



<p>Is it worth it to switch?</p>



<p>If you answered &#8216;no&#8217; to 3 or more of the above questions, you may benefit from switching providers. Answer the following 2 questions to be sure.</p>



<ol><li>Are you happy with your website and it&#8217;s host/developer as it is?</li><li>Are you willing to learn new technology if it will make updating your website easier?</li></ol>



<p>If you said yes to #1, there&#8217;s no need to switch. Sometimes having a great relationship with your developer can be more important than analyzing whether or not they are crossing their t&#8217;s and dotting their i&#8217;s.</p>



<p>If you said yes to #2, it might be a good idea to switch. If, however, it is easier for you to work with what you already have, switching providers may not be for you. If you struggle to learn new/unfamiliar technology, it can often be more taxing for you to switch to new technology than sticking with the tried-and-true. I have often heard of web developers selling a brand new design/system that will supposedly improve the old clunky system dramatically. The problem is, however, if everyone is accustomed to the old clunky system and finds that it&#8217;s &#8220;good enough,&#8221; switching to a new and better design can mean massive frustration for everyone involved.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/02/01/8-things-your-web-designer-developer-should-be-doing-for-you/">8 Things Your Web Designer / Developer Should Be Doing for You</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/02/01/8-things-your-web-designer-developer-should-be-doing-for-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>9 Things to Look for in a Web Professional&#8217;s Portfolio</title>
		<link>/2020/01/23/9-things-to-look-for-in-a-web-professionals-portfolio/</link>
					<comments>/2020/01/23/9-things-to-look-for-in-a-web-professionals-portfolio/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian McKenzie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 23:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.objektiv.digital/?p=41</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Back in the heyday of web marketing, having a website set you apart from the competition. It positioned you as an innovator and with the times. It meant getting more business than everyone else because people could find you on the internet when no one else was online. The simple fact of having a website [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/01/23/9-things-to-look-for-in-a-web-professionals-portfolio/">9 Things to Look for in a Web Professional&#8217;s Portfolio</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Back in the heyday of web marketing, having a website set you apart from the competition. It positioned you as an innovator and with the times. It meant getting more business than everyone else because people could find you on the internet when no one else was online. The simple fact of having a website was a distinct marketing advantage for your business.</p>



<p>These days, however, everyone has a website. Businesses big and small. Even businesses that could hardly be called businesses have a website. Having a website is no longer a novelty, it seems like it&#8217;s a requirement. Hiring a professional web developer can be costly. Using a platform like Wix or Squarespace can put you online for a comparatively small sum of money, but as many business owners can relate, having a website doesn&#8217;t seem to do anything for your business.</p>



<p>A storefront doesn&#8217;t feel like their website is getting people walking through their door, the realtor seldom gets leads filling out the contact form, the local artist never gets purchases on their E-commerce store. The reality is, having a website is no longer a competitive advantage. Worse yet, it seems to just add to the noise.</p>



<p>This directly translates to a common misconception about hiring a website designer/developer. Hiring a professional to build your website isn&#8217;t about getting you online. If you want to get online, make a Wix website. You don&#8217;t need to waste your money on a web professional. Hiring a web professional has and always will be about positioning your business at an advantage through the use of a website. The only thing that has changed is the tactics with which a web professional employs to help you gain that advantage.</p>



<p>At Objektiv Digital, we are relatively new to the web professional scene, and we wear that badge with pride. If you are hiring a web professional touting their 10 to 20 years of being in business, you are sure to be spending your money on someone who still thinks that simply being online is enough to gain you a competitive advantage. It&#8217;s not.</p>



<p>Building a website to gain an advantage over others is the cohesive unification of software development, graphic design, user experience design, copywriting, search engine optimization, social media management, and a comprehensive understanding of digital advertising. A website has and always will be the core of your digital marketing efforts. As the internet has grown in age and complexity, so has the way you utilize your website as the core of your digital marketing efforts.</p>



<p>Much like the entrepreneur of the &#8217;90s bold enough to make an investment in new technical landscapes, so must the entrepreneur of the &#8217;20s make the investment in understanding and utilizing the forefront of the digital marketing of today. Much like the difficulty of finding someone who knows how to make a website, it is even more difficult to find a web professional who understands the full picture of digital marketing.</p>



<p>Below is a list of things to look for when viewing a web professional&#8217;s portfolio. This is a shallow, basic list that doesn&#8217;t come close to covering the necessities of a digital marketing stack. However, you&#8217;ll be shocked to learn that most web professionals do not even meet the bare minimum of a website&#8217;s requirements:</p>



<ol><li>A clear call-to-action button in a colour that stands out from the rest of the page?</li><li>Is that call-to-action button visible on your screen BEFORE you start scrolling?</li><li>Does the header and/or subheading clearly describe what the business is and what they do?</li><li>When scanning the page, was there at least 3 to 5 paragraphs of text?</li><li>Did those paragraphs of text have only 2 to 3 sentences?</li><li>Did the headers suck you into reading the paragraphs?</li><li>Did the images complement the text?</li><li>Did the website speak to the company&#8217;s image?</li><li>Did the website talk about their customers, what their problem is, and position themselves as the guide to the solution?</li></ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/01/23/9-things-to-look-for-in-a-web-professionals-portfolio/">9 Things to Look for in a Web Professional&#8217;s Portfolio</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/01/23/9-things-to-look-for-in-a-web-professionals-portfolio/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Things to Think About Before Buying An E-Commerce Site</title>
		<link>/2020/01/13/5-things-to-think-about-before-buying-an-e-commerce-site/</link>
					<comments>/2020/01/13/5-things-to-think-about-before-buying-an-e-commerce-site/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian McKenzie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 23:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.objektiv.digital/?p=39</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In my quest to help small businesses grow, I see a common thread between entrepreneurial creatives — they all need an E-Commerce website. It makes sense. Etsy commissions are steep, and these days platforms like Instagram and Facebook give you hardly any exposure without paying for an ad to insert yourself in peoples&#8217; feeds. Not [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/01/13/5-things-to-think-about-before-buying-an-e-commerce-site/">5 Things to Think About Before Buying An E-Commerce Site</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In my quest to help small businesses grow, I see a common thread between entrepreneurial creatives — they all need an E-Commerce website. It makes sense. Etsy commissions are steep, and these days platforms like Instagram and Facebook give you hardly any exposure without paying for an ad to insert yourself in peoples&#8217; feeds. Not to mention the table fees at local market events keep going up, often making you feel lucky if you broke even for the event. The act of creating is what fills your soul, but when the time comes to make a living from your creations, the odds seem stacked against you.<br>I wish I had the answer to how to make it as a creator, but I don&#8217;t. I spent over a year experimenting with my project Curious Markings. I had a lot of fun, and I learned so many lessons about business, marketing, and being an entrepreneurial creative. Fortunately for me, I had the skills to build my E-Commerce site. To be brutally honest, I didn&#8217;t sell much. After turning my marketing efforts to growing Objektiv Digital, I quickly learned it wasn&#8217;t my marketing or sales skills that were lacking. The soul-crushing truth of it was, my creative endeavour didn&#8217;t resonate enough with any particular audience that I identified.<br>Looking back on everything I built for Curious Markings, it was all just a costly lesson — both money and especially time. For those who can&#8217;t make E-Commerce websites themselves; however, their lessons in dollar bills could be wildly more expensive than it was for me. Most people who sell websites will probably be confused by what I&#8217;m about to say: Don&#8217;t hire Objektiv Digital or anyone else to build you an E-Commerce website unless you&#8217;re 110% certain you know why you&#8217;re getting it, how to bring traffic to it affordably, and you have enough super-fans to support its development and ongoing fees.<br>Buying an E-Commerce website isn&#8217;t like buying a logo. It&#8217;s not like having business cards printed. It&#8217;s not even like having a normal website. E-Commerce websites can be much more costly to build for a multitude of reasons, including User Experience Design, payment processing, conversion tracking, cart abandonment recovery, etc. There is a vast number of technical and user-oriented things that need to be resolved.<br>Let&#8217;s say you have accepted the risks and had an E-Commerce site built. Maybe you got it for cheap from a friend, or you figured out how to make it yourself. Do you know what to do next? The reality is, even once you have an online store built, that store may as well be a physical storefront in an abandoned mall. You have a shop, but there is zero foot traffic. The only people who come by are your friends and family that you&#8217;ve invited. Maybe you put up an advertisement to bring in traffic. Perhaps a few people click the ad, and perhaps they don&#8217;t notice your store is in an abandoned mall. But, only a small fraction of them are going through with a purchase. Can you squeeze out as much of a Return on Investment (ROI) for those paid ads to come out ahead? The sad reality is that most people can&#8217;t, especially if they&#8217;re like me and have a product that doesn&#8217;t resonate with enough people.<br>At Objektiv Digital, we sell websites. We always ask, however, why do you need a website? At the end of the day, we want to be your partner in business. We are seeking long-term relationships. Sure, we can build an E-Commerce website for you. But, if that E-Commerce website isn&#8217;t making sales, you won&#8217;t be coming back for more help. When you can&#8217;t afford our future help, this means that our relationship has ended prematurely, and we have failed you as a company attempting to help grow your business.<br>The best advice I can give is to say do not buy an E-Commerce website as a creative/artisan unless you can answer yes to the following questions:</p>



<ul><li>Are you killing it on Etsy?</li><li>Are you killing it at local markets?</li><li>Are you getting several organic followers on social media each week?</li><li>If you&#8217;re running ads to get more followers, are you getting at least two followers per dollar spent?</li><li>If you&#8217;re running ads to make sales on Etsy, are you getting a consistently positive ROI?</li></ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/01/13/5-things-to-think-about-before-buying-an-e-commerce-site/">5 Things to Think About Before Buying An E-Commerce Site</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/01/13/5-things-to-think-about-before-buying-an-e-commerce-site/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Your “Marketing/SEO Guru” Subcontracting Offshore?</title>
		<link>/2019/12/21/is-your-marketing-seo-guru-subcontracting-offshore/</link>
					<comments>/2019/12/21/is-your-marketing-seo-guru-subcontracting-offshore/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian McKenzie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 08:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.objektiv.digital/?p=37</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Something that always comes up when I talk to small business owners is that when they buy marketing services, they eventually find out that the services they purchased are getting subcontracted to people that are not in North America. These people often have limited reading, writing, and comprehension skills in the English language. Today, I&#8217;d [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/12/21/is-your-marketing-seo-guru-subcontracting-offshore/">Is Your “Marketing/SEO Guru” Subcontracting Offshore?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Something that always comes up when I talk to small business owners is that when they buy marketing services, they eventually find out that the services they purchased are getting subcontracted to people that are not in North America. These people often have limited reading, writing, and comprehension skills in the English language. Today, I&#8217;d like to talk about why that may not be a good thing.<br>Your marketing services need to be culturally aligned<br>Firstly, if your marketer is not culturally aligned with your target market, that puts them at a disadvantage. To be an effective marketer, you must know the cultural nuances of the people who you&#8217;re selling a product or service. On a place like Vancouver Island, we have an identifiable culture even compared to the rest of British Columbia. Even Denman Island has a distinct culture from the rest of the Vancouver Island area. You especially couldn&#8217;t compare Victoria with Campbell River. Is someone from Bangalore, India going to have an awareness of these nuances?<br>You need people who can comprehend the nuance of the English language<br>Another thing to consider is a subcontractors&#8217; ability to read and write English. Let&#8217;s say you&#8217;re the owner of Salish Sea Foods in Comox, and your SEO specialist is subcontracting to someone to fine-tune your search engine optimization. Presumably, one of the target keywords you would want to hit hard is &#8220;Seafood Comox Valley.&#8221; Is the subcontractor going to know that &#8220;seafood&#8221; needs to be a single word? Are they going to spell it the wrong way, like &#8220;see food&#8221; or &#8220;seefood?&#8221;<br>Everyone wins when you keep it local<br>Lastly, if your marketing work is getting subcontracted elsewhere, that means less money in our local economy. There&#8217;s a lot of people who will articulate this point a lot better than I ever will. I will say, though, we have a fantastic community of business owners, local artisans and crafts[wo]men, farmers, ranchers, and more to create a sustainable local economy. The more we keep our business local, the more we all benefit.<br>The next time you hire anyone for digital services, I would highly recommend you ask where their employees and subcontractors are located. You ought to be getting every bit of value from the money you spend, and when your services are being sent off-Island, we all lose.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/12/21/is-your-marketing-seo-guru-subcontracting-offshore/">Is Your “Marketing/SEO Guru” Subcontracting Offshore?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/12/21/is-your-marketing-seo-guru-subcontracting-offshore/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 Things to Think About When Budgeting for A Website</title>
		<link>/2019/12/09/4-things-to-think-about-when-budgeting-for-a-website/</link>
					<comments>/2019/12/09/4-things-to-think-about-when-budgeting-for-a-website/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian McKenzie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 03:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.objektiv.digital/?p=35</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How will you bring traffic to your website?No traffic. This is always the biggest shock website customers get once their website goes live. The reality is, most web developers are experts in making websites and not in making website traffic. When buying a website, it is critical to start thinking about how you are going [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/12/09/4-things-to-think-about-when-budgeting-for-a-website/">4 Things to Think About When Budgeting for A Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>How will you bring traffic to your website?<br>No traffic. This is always the biggest shock website customers get once their website goes live. The reality is, most web developers are experts in making websites and not in making website traffic. When buying a website, it is critical to start thinking about how you are going to bring traffic to your website once you get online.</p>



<h1>1 — Paying for Search Engine Optimization (SEO) Services</h1>



<p>Getting to the top of Google and Bing search results means more traffic to your website. More traffic means more customers. Optimizing for search engines, however, requires a tremendous amount of expertise, the utilization of expensive SEO tools, and a wide range of skills, including proficiency in software development, graphic design, copywriting. As a result, SEO services can be expensive. Expect to pay in the range of $500 to $1,000 per month.<br>SEO Services: $500-1,000/month</p>



<h1>2 — Paying for digital advertisements such as Google Search and Facebook ads</h1>



<p>Another great way to generate traffic to your website is to advertise on search engines and social media. But, as many small business owners can attest to, navigating the advertising tools created by Facebook and Google can be a nightmare. Making a mistake can be extremely costly, and making a mistake is easy when you&#8217;re fumbling through complex interfaces.<br>The reason these interfaces are complex, however, is because they provide a great degree of power and control over effective digital advertising. A monumental task for a novice, yet a master of digital advertising can interact effervescently. Without a seasoned professional at the helm, digital advertising can be more like gambling at the casino than investing in an advertisement. Expect to pay $750 to $2,500 per month to get help making advertisements that net a positive return on investment.<br>Digital Advertising Management: $750-2,500/month<br>How will your website turn its visitors into customers?<br>At Objektiv Digital, we like to say that having a flashy website that does not make sales is like having a Ferrari sports car with no engine. If you are paying for a website to grow your business, it cannot fall short in the many problems that need to be resolved when creating a website.</p>



<h1>3 — Paying for copywriting optimized to convert website visitors into paying customers and leads</h1>



<p>The most powerful way to turn a website visitor into a customer is through the power of storytelling. To tell a compelling story designed for desired customer actions (such as walking into your storefront, booking an appointment, signing up to your newsletter, etc.), you need a professional copywriter that is seasoned at writing landing page copy that has headers that grab peoples&#8217; attention and body copy that compels visitors to click your call-to-action, all while cohesively telling an engaging story. Copywriting like this can cost between $850 to $1,500.<br>Landing Page Copywriting: $850-1500 one-time fee</p>



<h1>4 — Ensuring your website loads quickly, is mobile-friendly, and not unbearably ugly</h1>



<p>If your website is slow, is not compatible with phones (over 50% of web traffic is on mobile!), or is unprofessionally designed will instantly turn away your potential customers. The most compelling copywriting in the world won&#8217;t matter if your website takes more than 3 seconds to load — people will have already walked away before seeing a single word on your page.<br>Mobile users don&#8217;t want to have to fumble around zooming in and out, reading tiny text, clicking the wrong links, or any of the other problems a website not designed for a mobile device present. Not only is it a frustrating experience, but it reflects poorly on your company&#8217;s image. Speaking of a poor reflection of company image, an ugly design can do the same thing! If your website is ugly, people can have a hard time taking you seriously as a credible source of information. That is if they haven&#8217;t left your website in disgust already.<br>Professional web design and development: $2,000-10,000 one-time fee plus $100-300/month for maintenance<br>Conclusion<br>There are many factors that play into a holistic digital marketing approach to your website. Without proper consideration of all factors, your time and money put into a website can easily fall short. Having a great website is only half of the picture. Bringing traffic to it is equally as important. That traffic must convert, and they must find your website enjoyable to navigate.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/12/09/4-things-to-think-about-when-budgeting-for-a-website/">4 Things to Think About When Budgeting for A Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/12/09/4-things-to-think-about-when-budgeting-for-a-website/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Search Ads vs. Professional SEO Maintenance</title>
		<link>/2019/11/29/google-search-ads-vs-professional-seo-maintenance/</link>
					<comments>/2019/11/29/google-search-ads-vs-professional-seo-maintenance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian McKenzie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 16:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.objektiv.digital/?p=33</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Before we dive headfirst into how to compare Google Search Ads and Professional SEO Maintenance, let&#8217;s get some definitions out of the way:What is SEO?SEO is an acronym for Search Engine Optimization. Examples of Search Engines are Google, Bing, Yahoo, and Duck Duck Go. Optimizing your website for search engines means that when someone searches [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/11/29/google-search-ads-vs-professional-seo-maintenance/">Google Search Ads vs. Professional SEO Maintenance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Before we dive headfirst into how to compare Google Search Ads and Professional SEO Maintenance, let&#8217;s get some definitions out of the way:<br>What is SEO?<br>SEO is an acronym for Search Engine Optimization. Examples of Search Engines are Google, Bing, Yahoo, and Duck Duck Go. Optimizing your website for search engines means that when someone searches using terms related to your business, you are more likely to show up at the top of the results.<br>What is a Google Search Ad?<br>Whenever you search for something on Google, there is quite likely to be an ad that gets inserted to the top of the search results. It is clearly labelled as an ad and is often contextual to the search query. When you see this add, you get tracked as an &#8220;impression.&#8221; Companies pay Google for impressions on their Google Search Advertisement. When you click the ad, you are tracked as a &#8220;click-through.&#8221; Again, the company that paid for the ad pays extra for you clicking the ad. It&#8217;s almost like a cheat code to get put at the top of the search results.<br>Our journey with SEO and Google Search Ads<br>When you are first starting a business, you are desperately lacking two things: presence in the market you&#8217;re entering into, and expendable cash for marketing efforts (or cash for anything, really). When we (Objektiv Digital) first entered our market and began competing with more established firms, we were in the same situation. Luckily for us, one of the things we were trying to sell to others can be used for ourselves to grow our business: digital marketing. If we can&#8217;t effectively market ourselves in the digital space, why should we even call ourselves a business?<br>Because we can more cost-effectively do professional SEO maintenance ourselves, going that route is an easy answer. SEO, however, can take weeks or even months to take full effect. It&#8217;s a long-term game. When you&#8217;re first starting out, sometimes you need faster results.<br>As many entrepreneurs know, however, buying digital ad space can be risky if you don&#8217;t know what you&#8217;re doing. We often make the comparison of buying digital ads like playing blackjack at the casino. If you don&#8217;t know how to count cards, the house is always going to win. Sure, you may get lucky here or there, but the risk is too high. This gamble is why it&#8217;s important to either have your ads managed by a professional or to have regular consultations with a digital marketing professional to ensure your return on investment (ROI).<br>How to compare Google Search vs. Search Engine Optimization<br>Whether you&#8217;re paying for traffic or getting it organically, there will always be effort involved with getting results. The formula for knowing what&#8217;s best is rather simple. Ask these questions both about paid and organic search traffic:<br>Paid Traffic (Google Search Ads)</p>



<p>What are my click-throughs?<br>How much am I spending on Google Search ads?</p>



<p>Organic Traffic (SEO)</p>



<p>What are my click-throughs?<br>How much am I spending on SEO?</p>



<p>It&#8217;s as simple as comparing the numbers. If you&#8217;re spending $500/mo on professional SEO maintenance and getting 20 organic click-throughs vs. spending $250/mo on Google search ads and getting 43 click-throughs, the answer should be obvious which to invest in when you&#8217;re on a tight budget.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/11/29/google-search-ads-vs-professional-seo-maintenance/">Google Search Ads vs. Professional SEO Maintenance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Objektiv Digital</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/11/29/google-search-ads-vs-professional-seo-maintenance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
